Guide to the John Caughlan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
John Caughlan papers
1933-2003
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
0704
Caughlan, John,$d1909-1999
56.95 cubic feet 88 boxes, 3 oversize folders and two vertical files
Papers of an attorney and civil rights leader of Seattle, Washington
John Caughlan was a Seattle attorney and civil rights leader.
John Caughlan was born in Missouri in 1909, the son of a Methodist clergyman. The Caughlan family moved to Eastern Washington in 1911, living chiefly in Ellensburg, and then to Seattle where Caughlan graduated from Ballard High School and earned a B.A. at the University of Washington. In the early 1930s he enrolled briefly in a graduate program in English literature at Yale University but, feeling the discipline to be removed from the issues of the day (the problems of the Great Depression and the proposed solutions of the New Deal), he enrolled instead in Harvard Law School, graduating in 1935.
Caughlan returned to Seattle in 1937 after a short stint in New York. He worked briefly for a law firm but was fired after refusing to withdraw from a case in which he represented the Communist Party in a dispute with the city, which had revoked the Party's lease for the Civic Auditorium. In 1938 Caughlan became a deputy prosecutor for King County, although he took leave from this position to represent the Grays Habor Civil Rights Committee as they investigated the destruction of a public hall in Aberdeen, Washington. He also represented CIO official Dick Law at the inquest into the death of his wife, labor activist Laura Law.
Caughlan returned to the King County Prosecutor's Office in 1940, but was informed that he would only be permitted to resume work there if he would publicly denounce the Soviet Union. He refused to do so, was dismissed, and spent the rest of his career in private practice, having as partners at various times Siegfried Hesse, Leonard Schroeter, C.T. Hatten and Lee A. Holley.
Civil liberties and human rights were the two overarching concerns that informed Caughlan's professional activities. In the 1940s and 1950s he represented labor unions, union activists, the Communist Party, the Washington Pension Union, Henry Huff in the Smith Act case of United States v. Henry Huff et al., foreign-born residents facing deportation because of their political activities, and individuals accused of "subversive" or "un-American" activities in cases related to the Smith Act, the McCarran Act, and the McCarran-Walter Act. Hazel Wolf was one of these, threatened with deportation for Commumist Party membership. He also represented, with his partner C.T. "Barry" Hatten, a number of witnesses before the hearings conducted by the Washington State Legislature's Joint Legislative Fact Finding Committee on Un-American Activities, led by Albert F. Canwell, in 1947-1948. He also represented several individuals before the House Committee on Un-American Affairs (HUAC) at its Seattle hearings in 1954, and handled many cases involving screening of Coast Guard personnel. Caughlan had been charged with perjury in 1948, two years after stating in the course of testifying in an immigration case that he was not a member of the Communist Party. He was acquitted, but was himself called before HUAC in 1954 to face the charge again. In 1961 Caughlan was convicted of failure to pay income tax. He served six months in the federal prison camp on McNeil Island and was suspended from practice for thirty days.
Five of Caughlan's cases went to the United States Supreme Court; the most significant of these were Herbert Schneider vs. Willard Smith, Commandant, United States Coast Guard, 1968, which invalidated Cost Guard screening procedures for personnel on United States merchant marine vessels, and United States vs. Eugene Robel, 1967, which invalidated a section of the Subversive Activities Control Act (McCarran Act) which had prohibited employment at defense facilities of members of Communist-action organizations.
In the 1960s and 1970s Caughlan's focus moved to other issues such as segregation and racial discrimination, and human rights beyond the United States. He travelled to Mississippi in the summer of 1964 with other attorneys to assist in the defense of civil rights activists there; at home in Seattle he was involved in racially charged cases, working with members of the Black Panther Party and protesting inquest procedures (which were later changed) in the inquest into the killing of black activist Larry Ward by Seattle police. Caughlan handled many conscientious objector and Selective Service cases during the Vietnam War.
Human rights abuses by governments supported by the United States were an issue of ongoing concern for Caughlan. In 1977 he went to the Philippines as part of a delegation headed by former United States Attorney General Ramsey Clark, on a fact-finding mission to investigate human rights violations by the Marcos regime. During the 1980s he travelled several times to Central America, particularly Nicaragua, participating in a National Lawyers Guild mission in 1984 to observe the Nicaraguan elections, and also represented Central American refugees in their immigration cases. After the1981 murders of Filipino union organizers and anti-Marcos activists Silme Domingo and Gene Viernes, Caughlan was part of the legal team which represented the families in a civil suit against Ferdinand and Imelda Marcos and the Republic of the Philippines, and which was ultimately successful in proving a connnection between the Marcos regime and the murders. In the 1980s Caughlan was also much concerned with nuclear power issues, serving as part of the legal team that defended environmental activists of the Crabshell Alliance after their demonstrations against the construction of the Satsop nuclear facility. He also helped to draft state initiatives banning the importation of nuclear waste into Washington state, and requiring voter approval of the construction of nuclear facilities. In the late 1980s Caughlan became very involved with the Oakland, California-based Line of March, an organization dedicated to the study and analysis of the history and development of Marxist-Leninist thought.
In the 1990s, Caughlan was part of the legal team working on the case of Willem Eickholt, whose boat was seized by United States Customs officials upon his return from a humanitarian mission to Cuba. During this time Caughlan was active in the cause of independent and small party politics, and was involved in the effort to promote Ralph Nader's 1996 presidential campaign.
Caughlan served on the board of directors of the American Civil Liberties Union of Washington. He was a member of the National Lawyers Guild from its founding in 1937 and served on its executive board and committee and as chairperson of its International Committee. He was also a founder and an active member of the Seattle chapter of the National Lawyers Guild. Caughlan died on April 17, 1999.
Organized into 3 accessions.
Accession No. 0704-001, John Caughlan papers, 1933-1965
Accession No. 0704-002, John Caughlan papers, 1936-1999
Accession No. 0704-003, John Caughlan papers and photographs, 1936-2003
Case files, correspondence, pleadings, reports, newsletters, photographs.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact repository for details
Caughlan, John,$d1909-1999$vArchives; Dixon, Elmer; Huff, Henry P.; Law, Laura,$d -1940; Law, Richard; Domingo, Silme,$d -1981; Viernes, Gene,$d -1981; Wolf, Hazel,$d1898-2000; American Civil Liberties Union of Washington; Line of March Black Liberation Commission; Marine Cooks and Stewards Union; National Lawyers Guild; National Lawyers Guild.$bSeattle Chapter; Seattle Black Panther Party; Washington Pension Union; Washington (State).$bLegislature.$bJoint Legislative Fact-Finding Committee on Un-American Activities; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Washington (State)$xCivil rights; Washington (State)$xPolitics and government; Lawyers$zWashington (State)$zSeattle$vArchives; Antinuclear movement$zWashington (State); Cannery workers$xLabor unions$zWashington (State)$Seattle; Communism$zWashington (State); Communist trials$zUnited States; Communist trials$zWashington (State); Conscientious objectors; Governmental investigations$zWashington (State); Human rights$Human rights$zCentral America$zCentral America; Human rights$zNicaragua; Human rights$zMexico; Human rights$zPhilippines; Pension trusts$zWashington (State); Subversive activities$zWashington (State); Trials (Political crimes and offenses)$zUnited States; Case files; Correspondence; Newsletters; Photograph albums; Reports; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; African Americans; Civic Activism; Civil Procedure and Courts; Civil Rights; Labor History; Labor Unions
- John Caughlan papers, 1933-1965; 0704-001; 22.26 cubic feet 53 boxes and one oversize folder
  Arranged in two series:
  Personal and Professional Papers, 1933-1999
  Related Organizations' Records, 1950-1998
  This accession consists primarily of case files (which include correspondence, pleadings, reports, newsletters and related material) and documents Caughlan's cases from the 1930s and 1950s; significant cases include the Smith Act case of United States vs. Henry Huff, the Canwell hearings, the defense of Richard Law, multiple cases for the Marine Cooks and Stewards Union, and cases involving the Washington Pension Union.
  View selections from this collection in digital format.
  Open to all users.
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1933-1999
    Arranged by document type.
    - Case Files
      - Adams, Nona (Medical Care Program), 1951 (Box-folder 1/1)
      - Alcantro, Alex (Immigration), undated (Box-folder 1/2)
      - Allen, Eugenia B. (vs. Office Employees International Union), 1953-1961 (Box-folder 1/3-8)
      - Bigelow, William Charles, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Blichfeldt, Julius Bernhardt, 1939, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 1/10-2/1)
      - Boggs, Elizabeth, undated (Box-folder 2/2)
        See also: Communist Party. NW Dist. Committee
      - Bolongan, Aurelio Manac (Immigration), 1953 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Bonilla, Pete (Immigration), 1952 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Booth, John L. (Coast Guard Screening), 1951, 53 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Bradley, Stuart L., 1954 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Braun, Joseph N. (Seattle Housing Authority), 1958 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Bridges, Harry, 1949-1955 (Box-folder 2/8-10)
        Includes bound volume of ILWU Newsletters.
      - Building Service Employees International Union (BSEIU), 1945, 1947 (Box-folder 2/11-3/5)
        Includes bound volume of hearing transcript.
      - Butterworth, Joseph (Social Security), 1953 (Box-folder 3/6)
        See also: Canwell case
      - Carlson, Frank, 1950 (Box-folder 3/7)
        Also known as Solomon Skolnick.
      - Carmichael, E. Brooke, 1955 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - Caughlan, John, 1948-1957
        - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 4/2-3)
        - Caughlan vs. I.L.W.U., Local 37 (Charges for Services), 1953-1957 (Box-folder 4/4-5)
        - U.S. vs. Caughlan (False Statement re. Political Affiliation), 1948 (Box-folder 4/6)
        - Caughlan, et al. vs. Doyle, et al., (HUAC), 1956 (Box-folder 4/7-8)
      - Chiles, Stokes (Loyalty Security Screening), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - Civil Rights Congress vs. Seattle School District Board of Directors (Auditorium Use), undated (Box-folder 4/10)
      - Communist Party. Northwest District Committee
        - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 4/11)
        - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Boggs, Elizabeth and Heine Huff vs. City of Seattle (Auditorium Use), 1940, 1943 (Box-folder 4/13-14)
      - Communist Party USA vs. Belle Reeves, Secretary of State (Representation on Ballot), 1940-1948 (Box-folder 4/15-5/5)
        - Phil Frankfeld vs. Seattle Times (Libel), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Crain, James Joseph (Immigration), 1938, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 5/7-6/5)
        Crain also known as Crane or Cryan.
        Includes testimony of Joseph Butterworth.
      - Crouch, Paul (Witness), 1950, 1954, undated (Box-folder 6/6)
      - Dailey, Cecil E. vs. Housing Authority of the City of Seattle (Gwinn Amendment), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 6/7-10)
      - Daschbach, John (Referendum), 1951 (Box-folder 7/1-2)
      - De Lacy, Hugh (Libel), 1946-1948 (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Dennett, Eugene V. and Conrad H Espe,. (Affidavits), 1949 (Box-folder 7/4)
      - De Vries, Warntje (Regional Loyalty Board Hearing), 1950 (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Ferguson, John E.[James Stewart], 1950 (Box-folder 7/6-7)
        See also: Bridges, Harry (Immigration)
      - Finnish Workers Federation, Aberdeen - Hoquiam, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 7/8-9)
      - Fisher, Avalo Allison vs. U.S.A. (False Statement, Taft-Hartley, Non-Communist Affidavit), 1957-1962 (Box-folder 7/10-9/4)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley et al. vs. U.S.
        - Pleadings, 1952 (Box-folder 9/5-6)
        - Transcript Analysis, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 9/7)
        - Three bound volumes – Pleadings, 1952 (Box-folder 10/1-11/1)
      - Foster, William Z., 1949 (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Free Press Publishing Corp. vs. Ashley Holden (Libel), 1933, 1938, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 11/3-8)
      - Friel, Edward vs. Painters, Decorators, et al. Union Trial, 1947 (Box-folder 11/9-12/1)
      - Frontier Book Store, 1943 (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Fujimoto, Charles K. (Hawaii Case), 1955, undated (Box-folder 12/3-5)
      - Garph, Mike Biddle (Immigration), 1949-1958 (Box-folder 12/6-9)
      - Gladstein, Richard (Contempt), 1952 (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Gray, Lonnie (Screening), 1951, 1953 (Box-folder 12/11)
      - Hanson, David, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 12/12)
      - Henderson, Melvin (Murder Victim), 1944 (Box-folder 13/1)
      - Hernandez-Avila, Juan Manuel (Immigration), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 13/2-9)
      - Higa, Buster (Screening), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 13/10)
      - Hobson, Annie (Immigration), 1951-1956 (Box-folder 13/11-12)
      - Huff, Henry P.
        - Income Tax Matter, 1953, 1959 (Box-folder 13/13)
        - U.S. vs. Huff (Smith Act Violation)
          Also known as Huff vs. U.S.
          See also: Daschbach
        - General Correspondence, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 13/14-14/8)
        - General Correspondence, 1953-1954
          - Stanton, Munro, and Dean (Box-folder 14/9)
          - Lessor, Sarah, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 14/10)
        - Memoranda, 1952 (Box-folder 14/11)
        - Pleadings
          - Central Files Vol. I, 1952 (Box-folder 14/12)
          - Central Files Vol. II, 1953 (Box-folder 14/13-15/1)
          - Central Files Vol. III, 1953 (Box-folder 15/2)
          - Central Files Vol. IV, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 15/3)
          - Central Files Vol. V, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 15/4)
          - Appeal, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 15/5)
          - Appendix to Appellate Court, undated (Box-folder 15/6)
          - Bail, 1952-1953, 1958 (Box-folder 15/7-8)
          - Bail Bonds, 1952, 1957 (Box-folder 15/9)
          - Bail Bonds on Appeal, 1953-1954, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16/1)
          - Bail Reduction, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16/2)
          - Continuance, 1953 (Box-folder 16/3)
          - Dismissal, 1952, undated (Box-folder 16/4-6)
          - Exhibits, Subpoena ducus tecum, 1953 (Box-folder 16/7)
          - In Forma Pauperis, 1953 (Box-folder 16/8)
          - Indictment, 1952 (Box-folder 16/9)
          - Jury, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 16/10)
          - Motion to Strike, 1953 (Box-folder 16/11)
          - Motion for Leave to Travel, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 16/12)
          - Travel Post Trial, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 17/1)
          - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 17/2-3)
        - Transcripts, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 17/4-6)
        - Financial Records, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 17/7)
        - Subject Files
          - Exhibits, 1953 (Box-folder 17/8)
          - Fletcher, Jesse (Witness), 1953 (Box-folder 17/9)
          - Hartle, Barbara (Witness), 1954 (Box-folder 17/10)
          - Jury, undated (Box-folder 17/11)
          - Jury Panel Material - Voir Dire, undated (Box-folder 18/1)
          - Lautner, John (Witness), 1952 (Box-folder 18/2)
          - Smith Act Attorneys, 1952 (Box-folder 18/3)
          - Witnesses, undated (Box-folder 18/4)
        - Legal Research, 1949, 1950, 1958 (Box-folder 18/5-6)
        - Newsletters
          - Portlight, 1948 (Box-folder 18/7)
          - NW Citizens Defense Committee, 1953 (Box-folder 18/8)
        - Notes, 1953, undated (Box-folder 18/9-10)
        - Collateral cases
          - United States vs. Pennock, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 18/11)
          - United States vs. Daschbach (aka Daschbach vs. U.S.), 1953-1954 (Box-folder 18/12-13)
          - United States vs. Pettus (aka Pettus vs. U.S.), 1952-1954 (Box-folder 19/1)
          - Pettus and Daschbach consolidated, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 19/2)
          - United States vs. Phillips (aka Phillips vs. U.S.), 1950-1955 (Box-folder 19/3-6)
        - Clippings, 1954 (Box-folder 19/7)
        - Ephemera, 1952 (Box-folder 19/8)
          See also: Misc. oversize box 3
        - Miscellany, 1953 (Box-folder 19/9)
      - Huntamer, L.C. et al. vs. Earl Coe, Secretary of State (Affidavit of Candidacy), 1952 (Box-folder 19/10)
      - Iversen, Stanley O. vs. Seattle Gas Co. (Libel), 1954-1958 (Box-folder 19/11-20/1)
      - Jackson, Paul (Immigration), 1957 (Box-folder 20/2)
      - Jay, Cecil Reginald (Immigration), 1952-1958 (Box-folder 20/3-8)
      - Josue, I. Ignacio, undated (Box-folder 20/9)
      - Kairis, Milton (U.S. Coast Guard Screening), 1958 (Box-folder 20/10)
      - Kildall, William Ross (Screening), 1958-1962 (Box-folder 20/11)
      - Knaisky, Alex (Immigration), 1940-1954, undated (Box-folder 21/1-10)
      - Kohler, Charles (Immigration), 1949-1957 (Box-folder 21/11-22/3)
      - Kokoff, Joe [aka Mike K.] (Immigration), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 22/4)
      - Law, Richard (Murder of Laura Law)
        - General Correspondence, 1940 (Box-folder 22/5)
        - Transcripts, 1940 (Box-folder 22/6-7)
        - Pleadings, 1940 (Box-folder 22/8-9)
        - Clippings, 1940, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 22/10)
        - Miscellany, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 22/11)
        - Subject Files
          - Grays Harbor Civil Rights Committee
          - General Correspondence, 1940 (Box-folder 22/12)
          - Minutes, 1940 (Box-folder 23/1)
          - Reports, 1940 (Box-folder 23/2)
          - News Releases, 1940 (Box-folder 23/3)
          - Notes (Box-folder 23/4)
          - Ephemera (Box-folder 23/5)
          - Clippings (Box-folder 23/6)
          - Miscellany, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 23/7-8)
        - Collateral Case – Johnson vs. Moir, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 23/9)
      - Law, Richard vs. U.S. Commissioner of Internal Revenue (Income Tax Appeal), 1942-1943, 1950 (Box-folder 23/10-11)
      - Lemon, Ralph vs. Earl S. Coe, Secy. of State (Candidacy), 1948 (Box-folder 23/12)
      - Lind, Walter vs. Marine Cooks and Stewards, 1963 (Box-folder 23/13)
      - Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s International Union. Local 16, 1949 (Box-folder 23/14)
        See also: Bridges, Harry vs. Thomas Graham
      - Longshoremen’s and Warehousemen’s International Union. Local 37 vs. John P. Boyd, District Director Immigration & Naturalization Service., 1949, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 23/15-24/10)
        Includes ILWU Defense Committee Bulletins
      - Luckman, George (Immigration), 1944-1952 (Box-folder 24/11-25/6)
      - McConney, Norman Rowe (Immigration), 1959-1961 (Box-folder 25/7-9)
      - Machinists, International Association. Local 79 vs. Seattle Central Labor Council (Jurisdictional dispute), 1946-1948 (Box-folder 25/10)
      - MacKay, Hamish Scott, and William A. Mackie (Immigration), 1955 (Box-folder 26/1-2)
        See also: Niukkanen, William
      - Mangaoang, Ernesto A. (Immigration), 1950-1954, 1956 (Box-folder 26/3-27/3)
      - Marine Cooks and Stewards Union vs. Arnold, George
        - General Correspondence, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 27/4-6)
        - Pleadings
          - Superior Court – King County, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 27/7-28/5)
          - Supreme Court – Washington, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 28/6-29/2)
          - Supreme Court – United States, 1954 (Box-folder 29/3)
        - Statement of Fact, 1951 (Box-folder 29/4-30/1)
        - Transcripts
          - Superior Court – Washington – King County, 1951 (Box-folder 30/2)
          - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 30/3-4)
        - Testimony, undated (Box-folder 30/5)
        - Notes, 1951-1953, undated (Box-folder 30/6-10)
        - Research, undated (Box-folder 31/1)
        - Miscellany, 1949-1952, undated (Box-folder 31/2)
        - vs. Baker, Herbert, 1950-1952, 1959 (Box-folder 31/3-5)
        - vs. McMonagle, Marshall, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 31/6)
        - vs. Irwin – Lyons Lumber Company, 1948 (Box-folder 31/7)
        - vs. Petroleum Navigation Company, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 31/8-10)
        - vs. Rotan, Dan and Jack Taylor, 1948 (Box-folder 31/11)
        - vs. Tulip, George and Charles Birdsall, 1948, 1950 (Box-folder 31/12-13)
        - Other Cases
          - McMonagle, M.R. vs. Pacific Atlantic Steamship Company, 1946 (Box-folder 31/14)
          - National Labor Relations Board vs. Harris, Joseph, 1949 (Box-folder 31/15-16)
          - National Labor Relations Board vs. Pacific American Shipowners Association, 1952 (Box-folder 31/17)
          - Nichols, Charles vs. Dombroff, John Doe, 1949 (Box-folder 31/18)
          - Screening (U.S. Coast Guard), 1952 (Box-folder 31/19)
      - Mensalvas, Chris D. (Immigration), 1952-1954 (Box-folder 32/1-2)
      - Navarro, Nemosio Costales (Immigration), 1954-1957 (Box-folder 32/3-5)
      - Nelson, Burt (re: Subversive Activities Control Board), 1962 (Box-folder 32/6)
      - Nelson, Herbert L. vs. U.S. Army (Denied Commission), 1954 (Box-folder 32/7-8)
      - Niukkanen, William[William Mackie] (Deportation) (Box-folder 32/9-10)
        See also: MacKay, Hamish Scott and Wm. Mackie
      - Olson, Ardis (Navy Screening), 1949 (Box-folder 32/11)
      - Orloff, Stanley (Army Discharge)
        - Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 32/12-13)
        - Pleadings, 1952 (Box-folder 32/14-15)
        - Clippings, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 32/16)
      - Patrick, Robert E. adv. City of Spokane (Free Speech), 1947 (Box-folder 33/1)
      - Paulson, Clara and Gunnar (Denaturalization), 1954-1957 (Box-folder 33/2-6)
      - People’s Programs (Vincent J. Davis) vs. City of Seattle; Civic Auditorium re Paul Robeson Performance, 1952 (Box-folder 33/7-10)
      - Powell, John W. and Julian Schuman (Sedition), 1959 (Box-folder 33/11)
      - Powers, Patrick vs. Marine Firemen, 1957, 1959 (Box-folder 33/12-14)
      - Prudencio, Jose (Immigration), 1950-1954, undated (Box-folder 34/1-6)
      - Rabang, Henry Ragonton (Immigration), 1951-1958 (Box-folder 34/7-35/2)
      - Raimondi, Pietro Biagio (Deportation), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 35/3-5)
      - Reinecke, John, 1948 (Box-folder 35/6-7)
      - Rogers, Joseph, and Charles James vs. Mandin, J. and Monear, C., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 35/8-36/1)
      - Rystad, Tora (Immigration), 1955-1958 (Box-folder 36/2-6)
      - Sailor’s Union of the Pacific, 1950 (Box-folder 36/7)
      - Sana, Miguel Asuncion (Immigration), 1953 (Box-folder 36/8)
      - Sasieff, Boris (Immigration), 1949-1950, undated (Box-folder 36/9-37/12)
      - Scheiderman, William, et al. adv. U.S. (Smith Act – U.S. District Court, Southern District of California), 1951-1952 (Box-folder 38/1-39/4)
      - Shynn, Doo Sik (Immigration), 1956 (Box-folder 39/5)
      - Smith Ben H., 1964 (Box-folder 39/6)